Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals WEB.ARC.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals
2007-ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
WEB.ARC.001
19 websites
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals, first began by Tamiment in 2007, includes archived websites of individuals connected with the labor movement, trade unionism, radical politics, feminism, civil rights, social justice, prisoner rights, economic justice, radical art and music, alternative press, gay rights, anarchism, and peace and other movements. Website contain a variety of formats and materials, including pdfs, images, multimedia, event listings, blogs, and other web-based media.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library, New York University began web archiving in 2007 as part of a grant given by the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIPP) of the Library of Congress. As most unions, left movements, progressive organizations, and others stop creating ephemeral material and paper based collections and move most of their administrative and informational material to the web, Tamiment continued to document the changing face of the labor and left movement into the web era. Tamiment uses the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS) as their tool to capture and preserve websites. WAS was created in 2007 and Tamiment is one of its earliest partners. The California Digital Library provides the storage and infrastructure for the project.
Related Archival Material
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations
Printed Ephemera Collection on Individuals (PE 030)
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals, first began by Tamiment in 2007, archives websites of individuals connected with the labor movement, trade unionism, radical politics, feminism, civil rights, social justice, prisoner rights, economic justice, radical art and music, alternative press, gay rights, anarchism, and peace and other movements. This is an assembled collection, websites are chosen by the archivists.
These websites contain a huge variety of media, which include videos, pdfs, blog postings (including Tumblr and Wordpress blogs), petitions, news feeds, audio, message boards, and other media. These websites often act to document and update upon the individuals' activities, schedule upcoming events, build awareness of their causes or work, and information on projects the individuals are working on. Websites include writings and articles by individuals, examples of their work, or other activities.
The web collection documents the publicly available content of the web page, it does not archive material that is password protected or blocked due to robot txt exclusions. Although Tamiment attempts to archive the entirety of a website, certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (Youtube, Vimeo, or otherwise), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions. Archived websites are made publically available 6 months after their initial capture.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (including Youtube and Vimeo), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including Twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, Facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Robot txt exclusions also change the formatting of websites from their original display, websites with robot txt exclusions often display as an index.
Keyword and file-type search are also available to archived websites through the Web Archiving Service (WAS). To search for keywords within archived websites, click a site name link in the container list. From that page, click the "search" tab on the top left corner. From the search page, you can search by keyword, URL, and file type across all captures of one site or all the sites in the project.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Websites are selected by archivists and captured through the use of the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS). WAS uses a web crawler to copy the website at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy of the website.
Accruals
In general, crawls of sites are added quarterly. New sites are added to finding aids upon completion of 6 month embargo.
Existence and Location of Originals
Clicking on the links provided in the container list will take the user to the Web Archiving Service (WAS) page for the website. Sometimes the original website is still available on the live web and the original URL may be available. To get to the original web page, click the live link provided in the "Latest Starting URL" field on the WAS page.
Take Down Policy
Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor the website owner's request to remove their website from the collection. To request a site removal, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu
Custodial History
The archived websites were migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The links to California Digital Library were removed in October 2017.
Legislators -- United States.; Political prisoners -- United States.; Anarchists.; Radicals.; Communists.; Reporters and reporting.; Artists |x Political activity.; Prisoners |x Civil rights.; United States |x Politics and government.; Black nationalism |z United States.; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion
- Baraka, Amiri Archived Website, Jul 11, 2012 - Jul 11, 2013; Baraka, Amiri, 1934-2014
  Scope and Contents note
  Amiri Baraka, born in 1934, in Newark, New Jersey, USA, is an activist and author of over 40 books of essays, poems, drama, and music history and criticism. He writes on topics ranging from racism, national oppression, colonialism, neo-colonialism, self-determination, and national and human liberation. The website contains a biography, books, multimedia, and writings.
  Black nationalism |z United States.
- Bonosky, Phillip Archived Website, Nov 10, 2010 - Dec 17, 2013; Bonosky, Phillip
  Phillip Bonosky (1916-2013) was a Lithuanian American; author and journalist; and longtime member and activist of the Communist Party USA. He was on the editorial board of Masses and Mainstream, and the cultural editor, and later Moscow correspondent of the Party's newspaper, the People's Daily World. He was also on the editorial board of Political Affairs, the Party's monthly periodical. The web site includes his writings and a blog.
  Communists -- United States.; Lithuanian Americans.
- Bravo, Estela Archived Website, Apr 4, 2014-ongoing; Bravo, Estela
  Scope and Content Note
  Estela Bravo is a documentary filmmaker, working since the 1980s. Her work focuses on Latin America, especially Cuba She is known for her films "Ninos Desparecidos," "Holy Father and Gloria," "After the Battle," "Returning to Chile," "Maurice," "Fidel," "Who Am I? The Found Children of Argentina," and "Children in Debt." The website contains information on her films, especially her film, "Operation Peter Pan," film reviews, and her biography.
  Independent filmmakers.; Documentary films
- Chambers, Whittaker Archived Website, Jul 15, 2011 - ongoing; Chambers, Whittaker
  This site is the official website of Whittaker Chambers (1901-1961). He was a member of the Workers Party of America (1925), journalist at the Daily Worker and New Masses (1926- 1932), Soviet underground agent (1932- 1938), editor and senior editor at TIME magazine (1939- 1948), witness in the Alger Hiss Case (1948-1950), author of best-selling memoir Witness (1952), member of the founding editors of National Review, and (posthumous) recipient of the Presidential Medal of Freedom. This website contains blog posts related to the lives of other communists, information about the life of Chambers, and posting on current events related to Chambers' work.
  Espionage, Soviet -- United States.; Communists -- United States.; Hiss, Alger
- Davidson, Carl Archived Website, Jul 8, 2011 - ongoing
  Keep on Keepin' On is the blog of Carl Davidson, a former student leader of the new left of the 1960s, who served as a Vice President and National Secretary of Students for a Democratic Society. Currently he is a national co- chair of the Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism and a national board member of Solidarity Economy Network, advocating a mixture of market socialism and worker ownership. Recently Davidson led Progressives for Obama, now called Progressive America Rising, as an independent left- progressive initiative, in part to convince those on the radical left to pursue what he considers more pragmatic alternatives. He has also worked on a leadership level with United for Peace and Justice and its local affiliates. The website contains blog posts with analysis on contemporary politics.
  Socialists -- United States.
- Guthrie, Woody (1912-1967) Archived Website, Aug 16, 2009 - ongoing; Guthrie, Woody, 1912-1967
  The Official Woody Guthrie Website is also the home of the Woody Guthrie Archives, the Woody Guthrie Foundation, and Woody Guthrie Publications, Inc. Woody Guthrie (1912-1967) was a famous American folk singer, and Communist, best known for the anthem "This Land is Your Land."
  Communists -- United States.; Folk singers |z United States.
- Hay, Harry Archived Website, Jul 31, 2009 - ongoing; Hay, Harry
  The website is the official page of the film, "Hope Along the Wind: The Life of Harry Hay." Harry Hay (1912 –2002) was a labor advocate, onetime Communist Party member, and early leader in the American LGBT rights movement. He is known for his roles in helping to found several gay organizations, including the Mattachine Society, the first sustained gay rights group in the United States. The website gives information on the filmmakers, the making of the films, reviews and awards, and funders. The website also contains a transcript of the film.
  Gay rights -- United States.; Communists -- United States.
- Kunstler, William Archived Website, Jul 23, 2009 - Mar 14, 2010; Kunstler, Sarah
  This is the website of the film, Disturbing the Universe, created Emily Kunstler and Sarah Kunstler, which explores the life of their father, William Kunstler, who was a radical civil rights lawyer. In the 1960s and 70s, Kunstler fought for civil rights with Martin Luther King Jr. and represented the famed "Chicago 8" activists who protested the Vietnam War. The website contains information on the film. It was last updated in 2010.
  Kunstler, William M. (William Moses), 1919-1995 |x in motion.; pictures.; Lawyers -- Political activity -- United States.; Kunstler, William M. (William Moses), 1919-1995
- Law Office of Elizabeth M. Fink Archived Website, Apr 10, 2014-ongoing; Fink, Elizabeth
  This is the website for the Law Office of Elizabeth M. Fink, a civil rights and criminal defense attorney. Fink has worked on a number of cases including as the defense attorney for the Attica Prison riot class action suit. She also defended Silvia Baraldini, Dhoruba Bin-Wahad, and the United Freedom Front. The website also contains information on the other attorneys in the law office, Sarah Kunstler and Rebecca Heinegg.
  Legal assistance to prisoners -- United States.; Women lawyers.; Legal services -- New York (State) -- New York.; Attica Prison
- Lazar, Ernie Archived Website, Apr 15, 2011 - ongoing; Lazar, Ernie
  This website contains the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests Ernie Lazar requested from the FBI and other agencies. He has requested over 8900 FOIA requests totaling over 600,000 pages. Lazar is particularly interested in documents related to the John Birch Society and organizations and individuals recommended by the society. Organizations include the American Association for the United Nations, American Civil Liberties Union, Americans For Democratic Action, American Friends Service Committee, Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, Council on Foreign Relations, CORE, Foreign Policy Association, Highlander Folk School, League of Women Voters, NAACP, National Committee For A Sane Nuclear Policy, National Council of Churches, National Education Association, National Student Association, National Urban League, United World Federalists, UNESCO, UNICEF. Lazar also collects FOIA requests related to the Communist Party USA. The website contains his research based on the requests.
  Domestic intelligence |z United States.; Right and left (Political science).; Communism.; Anti-communist movements; John Birch Society
- Lazar, Ernie on Communist Party USA Archived Website, May 2, 2012; Lazar, Ernie
  This website contains the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests Ernie Lazar requested from the FBI and other agencies. He has requested over 8900 FOIA requests totaling over 600,000 pages. Lazar is particularly interested in documents related to the John Birch Society and organizations and individuals recommended by the society. Organizations include the American Association for the United Nations, American Civil Liberties Union, Americans For Democratic Action, American Friends Service Committee, Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, Council on Foreign Relations, CORE, Foreign Policy Association, Highlander Folk School, League of Women Voters, NAACP, National Committee For A Sane Nuclear Policy, National Council of Churches, National Education Association, National Student Association, National Urban League, United World Federalists, UNESCO, UNICEF. Lazar also collects FOIA requests related to the Communist Party USA. The website contains his research based on the requests. The updates for this page are contained in the main ernie124102 captures.
  Anti-communist movements -- United States.; Communism -- United States.
- Marquit, Erwin Archived Website, May 16, 2014-ongoing; Marquit, Erwin
  Erwin Marquit is a professor emeritus of physics at the University of Minnesota. He studied dialectical materialism and philosophy of the natural sciences. He is a longtime member of the Communist Party USA (joined in 1946), active on both the local (Organizational Secretary, Minnesota/Dakotas District) and national levels (International Department and Economics Commission). He was also a founder of the Midwest-based 501(c)(3) Marxist Educational Press (MEP—1976-2011) and editor of the 20 volumes of the Marxist Studies quarterly journal Nature, Society (NST--1986-2007). The website contains selected articles and his memoir.
  Philosophy, Marxist; Communists -- United States.
- Moloney, Mick Archived Website, Apr 11, 2014-ongoing; Moloney, Mick, 1944-
  Dr. Mick Moloney (1944-) is a musician, folklorist, and Global Distinguished Professor of Music and Irish Studies at New York University. He immigrated to the United States in 1973, earning a Ph.D. in folklore and folklife from the University of Pennsylvania. He has recorded and produced over forty albums of traditional music, acted as advisor for scores of festivals and concerts, and served as artistic director for the musical ensemble The Green Fields of America. In 1999, Moloney was awarded the National Heritage Award of the National Endowment of the Arts, the highest official honor of traditional artist can receive in the United States. The website includes event and concert listings, his discography, reviews, and his writings.
  Irish Americans -- Music.; Irish -- Songs and music.; Irish -- Music.; Irish |z United States |x Songs and music.
- Penley, John Archived Website, Mar 15, 2013 - ongoing; Penley, John.
  John Penley is a photographer and grassroots political activist associated with the squatters' rights movement and housing protests of the 1980s and 1990s in New York City's East Village and Lower East Side, as well as numerous other social causes. A former Navy serviceman, Penley took up photography as part of an effort to document the demonstrations, protests, and other political actions in which he took part, and in the process became a photojournalist. Hundreds of Penley's photographs have appeared in in publications including the New York Daily News, the New York Post, the New York Times, New York and Long Island Newsday, New York Magazine, The Villager, High Times Magazine, The Guardian, Art In America, WW 3 Illustrated, The Shadow, the East Village Eye, and many small political publications. They have also been distributed through press services such as United Press International and the Associated Press. The website contains photographs taken by Penley.
  Photographers |z New York (State) |z New York.; Photojournalism -- United States.; Documentary photography |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Sanders, Bernie Archived Website, Aug 21, 2010 - ongoing; Sanders, Bernard
  Bernie Sanders (born September 8, 1941 in Brooklyn) is the junior United States Senator from Vermont. Previously, Sanders represented Vermont's at-large district in the United States House of Representatives. Sanders also served as mayor of Burlington, Vermont. He is the longest serving independent member of Congress in American history, and a self-identified democratic socialist. He is the first person elected to the U.S. Senate to identify as a socialist. Sanders caucuses with the Democratic Party and is counted as a Democrat for the purposes of committee assignments, but because he does not belong to a formal political party, he appears as an independent on the ballot. This website is his official webpage.
  Socialists -- United States.; Legislators -- United States.
- Seeger, Peter Archived Website, Jun 21, 2012 - ongoing; Seeger, Pete, 1919-2014
  This is the official website of Pete Seeger (born May 3, 1919), an American folk singer and activist. The website contains information on his music, recent collaboration projects, and his label, Appleseed.
  Political ballads and songs -- United States.; Folk singers |z United States.
- Shakur, Assata Archived Website, Jul 30, 2009-Jun 24, 2014; Shakur, Assata
  Assata Olugbala Shakur (born July 16, 1947, as JoAnne Chesimard) is an African-American activist and escaped convict who was a member of the Black Panther Party (BPP) and Black Liberation Army (BLA). On May 2, 1973, she was involved in a shootout on the New Jersey turnpike, resulting in the death of a state trooper and BLA member Zayd Malik Shakur. Shakur spent six and a half years in prison before escaping in 1979 to New Jersey. She has been living in Cuba since 1984. This is her official support website.
  Political prisoners.
- Tambellini, Aldo Archived Website, Dec 7, 2012 - ongoing; Tambellini, Aldo
  Aldo Tambellini was born in Syracuse, New York in 1930 but grew up in Italy. In 1946, Aldo returned to the United States. With a full scholarship at Syracuse University he received a BFA in Painting, '54 and a Teaching Fellowship at the University of Notre Dame, MFA '59. In 1959, Aldo moved to New York City's Lower East Side. He founded the underground, "counter-culture" group, "Group Center," which organized alternative ways and non- traditional presentation of the artists' work to the public. He pioneered in the video art movement in the late 60's. In 1965, he began painting directly on film beginning his "Black Film Series" of which, "Black TV," (made using both film and video) was the winner of the International Grand Prix, Oberhausen Film Festival, 1969. Simultaneously, Aldo began a series of "Electromedia Performances" which organically brought together, projected paintings, film, video, poetry, light, dance, sound and live musicians. He founded the Gate Theatre, the only daily public theatre showing avant- garde independent filmmakers and in 1967, he co-founded with Otto Piene, the Black Gate, a second theatre which presented live multi-media (Electromedia) performances and installations. From 1976 to 1984, Aldo was a Fellow at the Center for Advanced Visual Studies at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. There he conducted workshops and organized with "communicationsphere" a series of international interactive Media Communication Projects. Since '84, he has concentrated on poetry and performing his poetry with music and video projection. In 2005 Aldo produced a digital film, "Listen" which incorporates his anti-war and political poetry, animation/video and film clips. This film won First Place in the "Short Experimental Film by an Independent Filmmaker" category at the New England Film Festival in October 2005 and at the Syracuse International Film Festival in 2006. In 2007 Aldo was awarded the "Lifetime Achievement Award" from Syracuse University at the 2007 Syracuse International Film Festival. The same year he received the Keys to the City of Cambridge from Mayor Ken Reeves in recognition of his contribution to the cultural environment of Cambridge. In 2010 Aldo was awarded a Gold medal from the Italian Government, Lucchesi Nel Mondo Organization, in recognition of his lifetime achievement in the Arts. The website contains examples of his art.
  Anarchists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Art |x Political aspects |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Zinn, Howard Archived Website, Jul 1, 2010 - ongoing; Zinn, Howard, 1922-2010
  This is the website of Howard Zinn (1922-2010), the noted radical U.S. historian and author of "A People's History of the United States." In addition to a biography and bibliography, the site contains print interviews, essays and commentary, audio and video, and information about The People Speak, the documentary based on the live performances of Howard Zinn and Anthony Arnove's Voices of a People's History of the United States.
  Historians -- United States.